-放手  让我过去  -你不能过去
- Let me go. Let me go. - You can't go.
菲利普
Philip.
-别多管闲事  -他是我朋友
- Stay out of this. - He's my friend.
我可做不了主
It's not up to me anymore.
-大伙儿说了算  -什么
- The people have spoken. - What?
我曾问你忠诚何在
I asked you where your loyalties lie.
你说在这里
You said here.
那好  证明啊
Well, prove it.
证明给大伙儿看
Prove it to us all.
-兄弟俩来场决斗  -没错
- Brother against brother. - Yeah.
胜者将获得自由
Winner goes free.
拼死一战
Fight to the death.
菲利普  求你了  别这样
Philip, please. Don't do this.
别这样
Don't do this.
-加油  莫尔  -上呀  莫尔
- Let's go, Merle! - Come on, Merle!
-好样的  莫尔  -好样儿的
- Yeah, Merle! - Yeah!
我的为人  大伙儿都清楚
Y'all know me.
我必将竭尽全力
I'm gonna do,
拼死作战
whatever I got to do,
以证明...
to prove...
我对小镇的耿耿忠心
that my loyalty is to this town!
你以为
You think,
这帮人会放过你吗
asshole's gonna let you go?
老弟  看我眼色
Just follow my lead, little brother.
咱俩现在就逃出去
We're getting out of this right now.
菲利普  让他们住手
Philip, stop this!
菲利普  快让他们住手
老弟  快点
Come on, little brother.
跟上
Stay close!
达里尔
Daryl!
莫尔  快跟上
Merle, come on.
走
Go!
快走
Come on.
咱们撤
Let's go.
跟上
Get on.
-咱们撤  -撤
- Let's go.  - Go.
《行尸走肉》
他们都在竞技场  走这边
They're all at the arena. This way.
你别跟着我们
You're not going anywhere with us.
紧要关头  一会儿再说好吗
You really want to do this right now?
快打开啊
Come on.
跟上
Come on, man.
瑞克  快点  我们走
Rick, come on. We've got to go.
走
Go.
还愣着干嘛
A little help would be nice.
快走  没时间了
We ain't got time for this.
咱们走
Let's go.
格伦
Glenn!
瑞克  瑞克
Rick. Rick.
瑞克
Rick.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我们带了位不速之客  你们先退后
Now we got a problem here. I need you to back up.
妈的  他来干什么
What the hell is he doing here?
-放下刀  -他想要杀死我
- Put it down! - He tried to kill me!
放下刀
Drop the sword.
-要不是他...  -我们能逃出来  多亏有他
- If it wasn't for him-- - He helped us get out of there.
没错  但他也把你打了个半死
Yeah, right after he beat the shit out of you.
-嘿  我也受伤了啊  -蠢蛋
- Hey, we both took our licks, man. - Jackass.
-闭嘴  -都别说了
- Hey, shut up. - Enough!
-放松  -把刀放下
- Relax. - Put it down!
别用枪指着老子
Get that thing out of my face!
小弟  你身边真是帮乌合之众
Man, look like you've gone native, brother.
怎么比得了你  居然和那疯子为伍
No more than you hanging out with that psycho back there.
是啊  但他挺有魅力的  这点我得承认
Oh, yeah, man. He is a charmer, I got to tell you that.
把你闺蜜安德利亚干得
Been putting the wood in your girlfriend Andrea.
-不亦乐乎啊  宝贝儿  -什么
- Big time, baby. - What?
安德利亚在伍德伯里镇吗
Andrea's in Woodbury?
总督的左右手
Right next to the Governor.
我叫你放下
I told you to drop that!
你认识安德莉亚吗
You know Andrea?
Hey, do you know Andrea?
她认识
Yep, she does.
她和金发美女在森林里
Her and blondie spent all winter
躲了一个冬天
cuddling up in the forest.
这位猛女还养了两只行尸宝宝
My new-being queen here had two pet walkers.
没胳膊  没下巴
No arms, cut off the jaws,
用链条锁着
kept them in chains.
-那光景真有趣  -闭嘴  哥
- Kind of ironic now that I think about it. - Shut up, bro.
是我们把她俩从森林里救出来
Hey, man, we snagged them out of the woods.
安德莉亚当时奄奄一息
Andrea is close to dying.
-所以她才跟他在一块儿吗  -是啊
- Is that why she's with him? - Yeah.
像虫子一样黏在一起
Snug as two little bugs.
现在打算怎么办  警长
So what you gonna do now, Sheriff, huh?
-被一群骗子  暴徒和懦夫包围着  -闭嘴
- Surrounded by a bunch of liars, thugs, and cowards. - Shut up!
天哪  快瞧瞧  真可悲
Oh, man, look at this. Pathetic.
-都揣着没子弹的枪  -莫尔  闭嘴
- All these guns and no bullets in them. - Merle, shut up!
要闭你自己闭  一群孬种
Shut up yourself! Bunch of pussies you roll--
混蛋
Asshole.
你可以一周后自己拆线
You can take those stiches out yourself in a week or so.
谢谢
Thank you.
懂医学知识真是好
Pretty nice having medical training.
没啥大用处
It'll only get you so far.
你被咬了
You were bit?
这小宝宝多大了
How old is the baby?
只有一周大
Barely a week.
老实说  我们没想到还能看到婴儿
To be honest, we never thought we'd see another baby.
真漂亮
Beautiful.
谢谢
Thanks.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
这不是我的孩子
She's not mine.
那妈妈在哪里
Where's the mother?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
天啊  你们受的苦真不少
Man, you people have been through the mill.
谁不是呢
Haven't we all?
外面只会更糟糕
It's only getting worse out there.
到处都是行尸
Dead everywhere.
只会让活人
And it's only making the living
不像活人
less like the living.
你们是我们碰到的唯一好人
You're the only decent folks we've come across.
你们一直在外面吗
You've been out there all this time?
我认识一个叫杰瑞的
I met a Jerry.
他总是杞人忧天
He's one of those survivalist nuts.
邻居都以为他疯了
Everybody on the block thought he was crazy.
总是在为世界末日准备
Always preparing for the end of the world.
-世事难料啊  -杰瑞料到了
- Who knew? - Jerry knew.
他在后院的棚屋下建了个地堡
He had a bunker under his shed in the backyard.
萨沙和我躲在里面  直到补给用完
Sasha and I stay there until we run out of supplies.
艾伦和本是我们从
Allen and Ben were the first two people we ran into
杰克逊维尔那个地堡爬出来后
when we finally crawled up out of that hole
最先碰到的两个人
around Jacksonville.
我们原先人很多
Used to be a bunch of us.
曾达到25个人
25 at one point.
我们的营地六七周前失陷了
Our camp was overrun six, seven weeks ago.
而堂娜
And-- and Donna,
她
she, uh...
我们会给她个体面的葬礼
We'll see that she has a proper burial.
非常感谢你照顾我们
I appreciate you taking care of us.
很久以来  我们都不敢相信生人
For a while, we didn't know who we were dealing with.
我们也是
Neither did we.
我们都分不清什么是人了
We've had a problem with what's people.
我一定是史上第一个
I must be the first brother in history
往监狱里跑的黑人
to break into prison.
那我就是第一个不想越狱白人
Makes me the first white boy that didn't want to break out.
泰尔西
Tyreese.
如我所言  我们的队伍还有其他人
Like I said, we have a much larger group.
团结而紧密
A close-knit group.
我建议你别过得太舒服
I wouldn't get too comfortable here.
我们不会惹事的
We wouldn't be a problem.
这不取决于我
It's not up to me.
那取决于谁
Then who?
拜托  你也看到我们是什么样的人了
Please, you can see what kind of people we are.
这样没用
It won't work.
-必须这样  -会制造事端的
- It's gotta. - It'll stir things up.
听着  总督现在可能
Look, the Governor is
正在赶往监狱
probably on the way to the prison right now.
莫尔了解他  而且我们需要帮手
Merle knows how he thinks and we could use the muscle.
他不能跟我们回监狱
I'm not having him at the prison.
你难道想让他跟我们住在同一区
Do you really want him to sleep with us
跟卡萝尔和贝丝一起
in the same block with Carol and Beth.
-他不是强奸犯  -他的同伙是
- He ain't a rapist. - Well, his buddy is.
昨晚之后他们已经不是同伙了
They ain't buddies no more. Not after last night.
莫尔跟我们住
There's no way Merle's gonna live there
大家都不会好过
without putting everyone at each other's throats.
你想让莫尔留在野外
So you're gonna cut Merle loose
带那个武士回去吗
and bring the last samurai home with us?
她也不能回去
She's not coming back.
她现在的状况没法独自生存
She's not in a state to be on her own.
是她带你们来救我们的
She did bring you guys to us.
但她半路失踪
And ditched us.
-至少让我父亲给她缝针  -她不稳定
-At least let my dad stitch her up. - She's too unpredictable.
说的对  我们还不知道她是谁
That's right. We don't know who she is.
但莫尔是兄弟
But Merle, Merle's blood.
不  莫尔是你的兄弟
No, Merle is your blood.
我的兄弟姐妹  我的家人此刻正站在这
My blood,my family is standing right here,
还有那些在监狱等着我们回去的人
and waiting for us back at the prison.
而你也是这个家族的一部分
And you're part of that family.
但他不是  他不是
But he's not. He's not.
你们别乱说
Man, y'all don't know.
好吧  我们自己照顾自己
Fine. We'll fend for ourselves.
我说的不是这个意思
That's not what I was saying.
没有他就没有我
No him, no me.
达里尔你不必那么做
Daryl, you don't have to do that.
反正我和莫尔相依为命惯了
It's always Merle and I before this.
-不要这样  -你真想这么做
- Don't. - You serious?
你就想这样一走了之
You're just gonna leave like that?
你们也是这么做的
You'd do the same thing.
我们要向卡萝尔怎么交代
What do you want us to tell Carol?
她会理解的
She'll understand.
替我向你父亲告别
Say good-bye to your pop for me.
达里尔  你真要走吗  达里尔
Daryl, are you serious? Daryl!
一定有其他办法
There's got to be another way.
我绝不会丢下他不管
Don't ask me to leave him.
我已经错过一次
I already did that once.
我们昨晚挑起了事端
We started something last night.
你没意识到吗
You realize that, huh?
没他就没我  就这样
No him, no me. That's all I can say.
你们保重
Take care of yourself.
照顾好小拽女
Take care of lil ass-kicker.
还有卡尔
Carl.
他是个坚强的孩子
He's one tough kid.
达里尔
Daryl.
走吧  哥
Come on, bro.
我们给你缝好针后赶紧离开
We patch you up and then you are gone.
他们说在哪里埋她来着
Where'd they say we could bury her?
场地后面  挨着其他坟墓
Back of the field near the other graves.
等下  等一下
Hey. Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
调整一下
Losing my grip here.
好吧
Okay. Come on.
绝好时机
Golden opportunity.
什么时机
For what?
只有一个小孩和女人
Little kid and a woman.
假意让他们帮忙  趁机夺取武器
Ask them for a hand, get a hold of those weapons.
-什么  -动作快点
- What? - We do it quick,
出其不意
they'll never know what hit them.
-不  等等  -我们是来埋葬唐娜的
- No. Whoa, whoa. - We're out here to bury Donna.
夺完枪之后再埋
We will, after.
-别这样  -看看这个地方
- Shut up. - Look at this place.
很安全
It's secure.
-他们是好人  -很简单的
- These are good people. - This will be easy.
一个小孩  一个女人
A little kid, a woman,
一个女孩和独腿老人
a girl and a one-legged old man.
别忘了还有个囚犯
Don't forget about the convict.
你难道准备谋杀一个婴儿吗
You gonna smash the baby's head with a rock?
-你有什么毛病  -你能不能正派点
- What is your problem? - How about a little common decency?
人不能做出这种事
This isn't what we do.
你还生活在过去  泰
You're living in the past, Ty.
你也是  这是适者生存的时代  很简单
So are you. This is survival of the fittest, plain and simple.
在这就能活  出去就会死
And here we live,out there we die.
我不会坐等他们团队的其他人回来
And I am not waiting around for the rest of their group
把我们赶出去
to roll in here and throw us out on our asses.
-没门  -你怎么肯定他们会赶我们走
- Not a chance. - How do you know that's gonna happen?
给你们拿了些工具
Got some tools for you.
非常感谢
It's much appreciated.
给我们就好
Yeah, we'll take it from here.
你们不需要帮忙埋尸体吗
You don't need no help with the body?
不用了  我们能行
No, we will manage.
如果要帮忙请尽管开口
Let us know if you need anything else.
谢谢
Thank you.
看一下刹车
Keep in the brakes.
我来搞定
I got it.
你没有杀他
You didn't kill him.
我们回去不是为了杀他
That's not why we went back.
对  你回去是为了救出达里尔
No. That's right. You went back for Daryl.
可现在达里尔走了  总督依然活着
And now he's gone again and the Governor is still alive.
救出达里尔是头等大事
Daryl was the priority.
我应该跟你们一起去的
I should have been there with you.
可你受伤了
You are in no condition.
难道我女友没受伤吗
But my girl friend was?
格伦  这不是你我之间的事
Glenn, this isn't about us.
我应该去的
I should have been there.
你没有和我们一起去
Hey, hey, you didn't come back with us
是因为你伤得连站都站不稳
because you could barely walk.
-那她呢  -我怎么了
- What about her? - What about me?
你知道他对她做了什么吗
Do you know what he did to her?!
别提这事
Leave it alone!
-你知道吗  -我们走吧
- Do you know? - Let's go.
我们费了这么大功夫  冒了这么大的险
After all that effort, all the risk we took,
达里尔就这样离开我们跟着莫尔走了
Daryl just takes off with Merle?
他有他的理由
Well, he had his reasons.
继续自欺欺人吧  瑞克
Yeah, you keep telling yourself that, Rick.
改变不了我们惹上大麻烦的事实
Don't change the fact that we're up to our necks in shit.
你希望我回去找他  求他回来吗
You want me to turn the car around, beg him to come back?
热烈欢迎莫尔回归吗
Throw down a welcome mat for Merle?
我们已经跟他打过交道了
This is the hand we've been dealt!
把车弄走赶紧回去吧
Let's just get this out of here and get back.
回去休息一下  有话回去再说
Get some rest. We can talk out there.
要谈你们谈  我已经谈够了
No, you guys do all the talking you want. I'm done.
多少人受伤
How many injured?
九个
Nine.
斯蒂文斯在照看他们
Stevens has it covered.
他人呢
So where is he?
-在房间里  -然后呢
- In his apartment. - And?
他不肯开门
He wouldn't open the door.
说他很忙
Said he was in the middle of something.
大叫大嚷的
Talk on the hell.
开门
Open the gate!
冷静一下
Calm down, people.
-退开  -这里不安全  我们要离开
- Back away. - It's not safe here. We want to leave.
-外面可都是行尸  -让我们走
- There's biters out here, lady. - Let us out.
退后
Get back!
我说过让你退后
I told you to get back.
没有人可以离开
Nobody leaves.
马丁内斯  有行尸过来了
Hey, Martinez, we got biters.
干掉它们
All right, take them out.
大家都冷静下来
Everybody calm down.
我们不能再待在这里了
We can't stay here anymore.
这里太疯狂了
This place is crazy.
拜托  让我们走吧
Please, let us go.
凯伦  外面太危险  你不能出去
Karen, you don't want to go out there. It's too dangerous.
-我们宁愿冒一下险  -拜托
- Yeah, well, we'll take our chances. - Please!
别鸣喇叭
Hey, knock off the horn.
-别鸣喇叭  -马丁那
- Knock off that horn. - Matina.
-下车  -放下枪
- Get out of the car. - Put the gun down.
-出来  -别
- Get out of the car. - Hey. Hey. Hey.
不许动手
Don't hurt him. Don't hurt him.
我可不听你指挥
Hey, I don't take orders from you.
这些人吓坏了  用枪指着他们只会让他们更慌
These people are scared. Shoving a gun in their face won't help.
总督在哪
Where is the Governor?
这里发生暴乱了
There's a riot out here. Come on.
你这是添乱
You're making things worse.
是吗
I am?
-怎么回事  -走
-What the hell? - Move!
退开  退开
Get back, get back.
天啊
Oh, my God.
救救他
Help him.
拜托  救救他
Somebody, please?
救命
Help.
救救他
Do something.
真安静
It's so quiet.
都快忘了这个世界以前有多么吵
It's easy to forget how loud the world used to be.
我以前经常抱怨这个世界太吵了
I used to complain about it all the time.
车流  工地
Traffic, construction,
汽车报警器  噪音污染
car alarms, noise pollution.
现在要是能听到喷气式客机的声音该多好
What I wouldn't give for the sweet sound of a jumbo jet.
要是我们都能上飞机就更好了
It'd be even sweeter if we were all on it.
你妈妈很为你骄傲
Your mom was proud of you.
骄傲什么  对她恶声恶气的吗
For what? Being mean to her?
你不能这么想
No, you can't think about that.
我脑子里想的全是这个
It's all I think about.
但愿是他们
Please be them.
是他们  快
It's them. Hurry.
-开上去  我们上面见  -好
- Drive 'em up. I'll meet you there. - Okay.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
-赫谢尔在哪儿  -他在牢房里
- Where's Hershel? - He's in the cell block.
达里尔在哪儿
Where's Daryl?
没事  他还活着
It's all right. He's alive.
我们碰到了他哥哥
We ran into his brother.
他们离开了
They went off.
他离开了
He left?
达里尔离开了
Daryl left?
他走了吗
He's gone?
他还回来吗
Is he coming back?
走了吗
Gone?
奥斯卡呢
And Oscar?
死了
No.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell was that?
你在众目睽睽之下朝那人脑袋开了一枪
You put a round in a man's head in front of all those people
然后就这么离开了
and just take off?
-你得和大伙谈谈  -为什么
- You have to talk to them. - Why?
他们惊慌失措  准备夺门而逃
They're panicking. They were ready to charge through those gates.
让他们去吧
So let 'em.
那些人活不到明天
Those people won't last a day.
他们以前过得很好
Those people have had it easy.
又是烧烤又是野餐  都到此为止了
Barbecues and picnics. That ends now.
这是你惹下的乱子  别怪他们
Don't blame them for the mess that you created.
大家很害怕
They're scared.
我不再保护他们了
Well, I'm through holding their hands.
我们正处于战争中
We're at war.
你该看得出
You should have seen that.
那为什么达里尔在这儿
So why was Daryl here?
他参与恐怖袭击了吗
Was he part of the assault?
为什么  他为什么会那样做
Why? Why would he do that?
他为他的朋友们而来
He came for his friends.
那些人你也认识
Other people you know.
格伦和玛姬
Glenn and Maggie.
莫尔发现他们在逃亡
Merle scooped them up on the run.
就把他们带回来问他弟弟的下落
Was holding them to find out where his brother was.
我的朋友们还活着 而且我们还互相开枪
My-- my friends are still alive and we're shooting at each other?
你想处决他们
You're trying to execute them?
你的朋友们杀了六个好人
Your friends killed six good people.
克罗利  提姆  加尔朱洛
Crowley, Tim, Gargulio,
艾森伯格  鲍勃·亚当斯
Eisenberg, Bob Adams.
海莉
Haley.
外面的那人  理查德·法斯特  是第七个
That man out there, Richard Faster, he makes seven.
这就是你朋友们的所作所为
So that's what your friends did.
你为什么不告诉我他们在这儿
Why didn't you tell me they were here?
你瞒着我  而我们却在...
You kept that from me while we were...
你在这里只是个访客
You're just a visitor here.
路过而已
Just passing through.
我为什么要告诉你
So why should I tell you?
不要这样
Don't do that.
不要赶走我  现在不行
Don't drive me out. Not now.
什么事
What is it?
整个镇上的人都出来了
The whole town is out on the street.
情况可能再次变糟
It could get ugly again.
带你姐姐进去
Take your sister inside.
去吧
Go on.
你平安归来了 和以往一样
You came through, like always.
我们手头上好像又有新问题了
Sounds like we have a new problem on our hands.
-是啊  -你看清楚他的样子了吗
- Yeah. - You get a good look at him?
他让达里尔和莫尔自相残杀
He had Daryl and Merle pitted against each other.
一群人欢呼着  让他们生死决斗
A crowd cheering for them to fight to the death.
什么样的变态会这么做
What kind of a sick mind does that?
林子大了什么鸟都有
A kind this world creates.
怎么了  婴儿不好吗
What's wrong? The baby?
不  婴儿很健康
No, the baby, she's healthy.
吃得香  睡得甜
Eats like a horse, sleeps like a rock.
那是怎么回事
So what is it?
他不怎么健谈  是吧
Not exactly a chatterbox, is he?
耐心点
Be patient.
等时机成熟  让我来谈
When it's ready, let me do the talk.
她的眼睛有点像洛莉
She kind of has Lori's eyes.
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
各位  请
Everyone, if I could--
请听我说
if I could have your attention.
-各位  -好了  大家不要说话
- Everyone. - All right, everybody shut up!
谢了
Thank you.
防线周围的行尸都被消灭了
The biters on the perimeter have been dispatched.
-围墙也修好了  -暂时而已
- The fences have been repaired. - For now.
总督在哪
Where's the Governor?
他的状态
His-- his condition is...
不太稳定
unsteady.
他的伤口
The wound he suffered--
-我们的朋友被杀了  -他对理查德开枪
- Our friends were killed, man. - He shot Richard.
我们都遭罪了  我们想要说法
I mean, we've all suffered. We want answers.
你说得对  卡伦  你说得对
You're right, Karen. You're right.
我们都经历了痛苦
Every one of us has suffered.
死的人太多了我们都来不及
We don't even have funerals anymore because
举行葬礼
the death never stops.
我们不会是从前的我们了
We'll never gonna be the same.
永远不会了
Ever.
那我们要怎么做
So what do we do?
我们要努力  找到继续前行的力量
We dig deep and we find the strength to carry on.
团结一致  重建家园
We work together, and we rebuild.
不仅仅重建围墙
Not just the fences,
大门和社区
the gates, the community,
也要重建我们自己
but ourselves.
我们的心  我们的思想
Our hearts, our minds.
很多年以后  当人们
And years from now, when they write about this plague
编写这次瘟疫的历史时
in the history books,
他们会写到世外桃源小镇
they will write about Woodbury.
我们坚持过来了
We persevered.
-是的  他们会的  -世外桃源小镇
- Yeah, they will. - Woodbury.
你掌握了技巧呢
You've got a knack for that.
只是做好份内事
Just trying to do my part.
索菲亚曾经像闹钟一样凌晨三点
Sophia used to wake the neighbors.
准时吵醒邻居
3 a.m.like clockwork.
在她安静下来前  爱德都得睡在朋友家
Ed stayed at a friend's most nights till she calmed down.
我一直想要个孩子
Al always wanted a child
如果没有达里尔她活不下来
She wouldn't have made it if Daryl hadn't been here.
他无法承受再失去别人
He couldn't stand to lose anyone else.
听起来像他
Sounds like him.
我不明白他为什么非要走
I don't see why he had to leave.
莫尔听起来像个混蛋
Merle sounds like a jerk.
莫尔那样的人能给你洗脑
Men like Merle get into your head,
让你觉得被虐待罪有应得
makes you feel like you deserve the abuse.
对达里尔也是吗
Even for Daryl?
我和一年前判若两人
I'm hardly the woman I was a year ago,
如果爱德现在活着从那扇门走进来
but if Ed walked through that door right now
让我跟他走
Breathing and told me to go with him.
我希望我会告诉他去死
I'd like to think I'd tell him to go to hell.
你会的
You would.
不重要了
It doesn't matter.
没有他我们很弱
We're weak without him.
我们也会挺过来的
We'll get through this, too.
泰尔西和他的朋友看起来很厉害
Tyreese and his friends seem capable.
他走了我很生气
I'm pissed at him for leaving.
别这样
Don't be.
达里尔有他自己的原则
Daryl has his code.
这个世界需要那样的男人
This world needs men like that.
乖
Oh. Hello.
-好了  -装她正好
- There. - She fits perfect.
是啊
Yeah.
躺得舒服吗
Wait. You cozy in there?
(小拽女)
被揍得这么狠
You got worked over good.
骨头没断很令我惊讶
Surprised no bones were broken.
达里尔哥哥干的好事
Coutsey of Daryl's brother.
你俩还好吗
You two all right?
谢谢你保护她
Thanks for looking out for her.
如果
If anything...
我去看看她  你还要点什么吗
I'll go check on her. You need something else?
好吧
Okay.
你也是一样
Same thing goes for you.
如果你有什么不测的话
If anything worse than this happen to you.
你像我的亲儿子一样  格伦
You're like my own son, Glenn.
需要我给你看看吗
You got something needs looking at?
格伦没事吧
Is Glenn alright?
自己去看吧
Go see.
你们两个好像有事瞒着我
You two seem to be holding something back.
想告诉我发生什么了吗
You want to tell me what happened?
你能自立我很欣慰
I rest easy knowing you can handle youself.
你继承了你母亲的精神
You've got your mother's spirit.
还有她的固执
And her stubbornness.
饿了吗
You hungry?
没有
No.
别再离开我了
Don't disappear on me.
她昏睡不醒
She's out like a light.
一定几天没睡了
Must be days since she slept.
你看上去也很疲惫
You look pretty shot yourself.
要多久她才能上路
How long before she can travel?
照顾好她
Keep an eye on her.
可以肯定她得了脑震荡
Pretty sure she has a concussion.
就是醒了也得几天时间恢复
Couple of days if she's up.
托马斯发飙时
Whenever Tomas went off,
奥斯卡总帮着我
Oscar always stood up for me, you know?
他是我朋友
He was my friend.
他是去战斗的
He went out fighting.
那现在怎么办
So what now?
你认为总督会报复吗
You think the Governor will retaliate?
-是的  -让他尽管放马来
- Yes. - Let him try.
听说他领导一个镇的人
Sounds like he's got a whole town.
我们人少枪少
We're outnumbered and outgunned.
也许我们可以找人支援
could use some reinforcements.
我叫泰尔西
I'm Tyreese.
萨沙  艾伦  本
Sasha, Allen, Ben.
你们怎么进来的
How'd you get in?
监狱管理区着过火
Fire damage to the administrative part of the prison.
墙塌了
Wall's down.
那边全都是行尸
That side's completely overrun with walkers.
你们怎么活到现在的
How'd you get this far?
不全活着  我们失去了堂娜
We didn't. We lost our friend Donna.
他们在健身馆迷了路
They were lost in the gyms.
是你把他们带来的吗
You brought them here?
他别无选择
He had no choice.
你们朋友的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about your friend.
我们都感同身受
We know what that's like.
赫谢尔说你们需要援兵
Hershel said you could use some extra hands.
对付僵尸我们也不陌生
We're no stranger to hard work.
我们会自己出去找食物  不麻烦你们
We'll go out and get our own food, stay out of your hair.
如果有人跟你们过不去
You got a problem with another group,
我们也会帮忙
we'll help with that, too.
不遗余力
Anything to contribute.
不行
No.
求求你了
Please.
《十个小印第安人》英国推理小说  故事中十人依次离奇死亡
外面就像《十个小印第安人》
It's like "10 Little Indians" Out there.
只是主人公换成了我们
It's just us now.
不行
No.
我们好好谈谈吧
Let's talk about this.
我们不能眼看着...
We can't just keep...
我们经历过
We've been through this.
托马斯和安德鲁的加入  结果怎样
With Tomas, Andrew. Look what happened.
阿克塞尔和奥斯卡和他们不同
Axel and Oscar weren't like them.
奥斯卡现在人呢
And where's Oscar now?
我担不起这个责任
I can't be responsible.
你把我们赶走
You turned us out,
责任就得你承担
you are responsible.
瑞克
Rick.
你为我们做了很多
You've done so much for us.
我很感激  我们都很感激
I appreciate that. We all do.
我们的命都是你给的
We owe you our lives.
你说什么我们做什么
We've done everything you asked without question.
但你现在做的是错的
And I'm telling you you're wrong on this.
你得开始学会给他人生存机会
You got to start giving people a chance.
是啊
Yeah.
不  不
No, no.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
不
No.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
你在这里干什么
Why are you here?
-你想让我做什么  -爸爸
- What do you want from me? - Dad?
你为什么...  不
Why are you... no.
我帮不了你  走开
I can't help you. Get out!
走开
Get-- get out!
没事儿
It's all good.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
没事儿的  瑞克  你不需要...
Hey, easy, Rick. There's no need to...
你已经不属于这里了  求求你  走开
You don't belong here! Get out! Please!
冷静点  老兄  冷静
Relax, brother. Relax.
走开  走开
Get out! Get out!
我们走  我们这就走
We'll leave. We're going.
行吗  没必要动枪
Okay? Ain't nobody got to get shot here.
我们现在就走
We are going.
-好了  我们走了  -快走  快走
- Okay, we're going. - Just go! Go! Go!